Partial Inventory of the V. G. Ulitin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
V. G. Ulitin papers
1920-2006
2009C14
Ulitin, V. G. (Vladimir Grigor'evich), 1905-
57 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 4 oversize boxes, oversize memorabilia (27.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to Russian émigré affairs, Russian culture, Cossack history and Cossacks in emigration, and post-World War II resettlement of Russian displaced persons.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian-American educator and relief worker.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to Russian émigré affairs, Russian culture, Cossack history and Cossacks in emigration, and post-World War II resettlement of Russian displaced persons.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Russians--United States.; Cossacks.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; International relief.; Russia--Civilization.
Partial Collection Contents
- Sound recordings, 1986-1998; undated (Box 56)
  Transcripts of some sound recordings are in box 55
  - Sound recording of a liturgy, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002851
    Sounds like a copy of a record.
  - Sound recording of Reverend L. Kishkovsky recorded speech: Church and State Relations in Russia Today, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002852
    A talk on the history of religion in Russian History. Kishkovsky concentrates on post-Soviet Union 1990s Russia. He believes that if Russia wants to have a relationship with the Russian Orthodox Church, some amount of restitution is needed. The question-and-answer session that follows touches on the Methodist Church for some time. For dating purposes: Kishkovsky refers to Boris Yeltsin as the current president of Russia and to "President Clinton."
  - Sound recording of music, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002853
    MAPWN - Marches
  - Sound recording of a liturgy, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002854
  - Sound recording of Russian poetry and prose, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002855
    Read by V. Markov
  - Sound recording in Russian, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002935
    Two voices; one male, one female. At the end, it is one female voice and a child's voice.
  - Sound recording of radio broadcasts concerning vocal music, undated (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002936
    Most of the tape is an audio documentary on Maria Callas. The rest is an unrelated concert of voice and piano from the Library of Congress.
  - Sound recording of the Valentin Berezhkov memorial service, 1998 November 24 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002937
    Family, friends, and colleagues comment on the life and character of Berezhkov. They recognize him as an eyewitness to history, a spirited political analyst, and a lover of jokes.
  - Sound recording of an interview, 1998 November (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0002938
    A woman interviews a man concerning his family and life in Russia/Soviet Union.
  - Sound recording of an interview, 1998 July 28 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0003067
  - Sound recording of an interview with Ulitin, 1998 June 11 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0003075
    A woman interviews Ulitin. Topics include his life growing up, family, and Cossacks.
  - Sound recordings of interviews with Ulitin, 1986 October 23 - 1987 July 17 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0003076
    Discussing the spirit of the Cossack people, especially in relation to state power.
  - Sound recordings of interviews with Ulitin, 1986 October 21 - 1987 July 17 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0003246
    A discussion of his family, past, and relationship with the church.
  - Sound recordings of interviews with Ulitin, 18 Sep 1986 and; 28 Jul 1988 (Box 56)
    Use copy reference number: 2009c14_a_0003247
- The collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu